Guide to the Josephine Harris Stewart Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Josephine Harris Stewart Papers
1920-2000
2000-001
Stewart, Josephine Harris
12.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The collection arrived in little discernable order and the processor in consultation with the archivist has imposed an order.
Biographical Information:
Josephine Harris Stewart was a prominent social worker and activist who is recognized as a pioneer in the field of social group work. She was born June 9, 1924 in Cincinnati, Ohio, and is of Hungarian Jewish descent. She received a bachelor of science degree in education in 1945 from the University of Cincinnati Teachers College. Following graduation, she enlisted in the Women's Army Corps and was assigned as an occupational counselor in Des Moines, Iowa, until her discharge in September 1946. She graduated in 1949 from the University of Pittsburgh with a master of social work degree, with a specialization in social group work. In 1960 she earned an advanced curriculum certificate in community organization from the University of Pennsylvania, and completed all the requirements, except for the dissertation, for a doctoral degree in social work.
Stewart's early career encompassed a number of jobs in the social work field, including teaching and social work practice at public and private social welfare agencies and hospitals. She was a social group worker at the Menninger Clinic in Topeka, where she was the first social group worker in Kansas; the LaRue D. Carter Memorial Hospital in Indianapolis, Indiana, where she served as psychiatric social work supervisor; and the Rollman Institute of Psychiatry in Cincinnati, Ohio, where she was a psychiatric social work educational supervisor. She was also a family counselor at Jewish Family Service of Philadelphia. Her teaching positions include serving as field work instructor and lecturer in social group work at Indiana University and lecturer in social welfare and field work consultant at the University of California, Berkeley. From 1964 to 1975, Stewart was an assistant professor and lecturer at West Virginia University, where she taught a number of social work courses. In 1975 she moved to Houston, where she was the first social worker hired at Methodist Hospital. She retired from Methodist shortly before her death from lung cancer on September 26, 1990.
Stewart was an activist for gay/lesbian and women's issues, particularly during her years in Houston. She was a charter member of the National Association of Social Workers and served the organization as national chairman on gay/lesbian issues during the 1980s. Stewart was also a co-founder of the Houston Area Women's Center.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Bylaws (administrative records); Correspondence; Ephemera; Pamphlets; Photographs
Personal Name:
Stewart, Josephine Harris
Topical Term:
Counseling; Social service; Women's rights
Acquisition Information:
Donated by Margaret Hardeman-Muye, 2000
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Related Materials:
Harris County Women’s Political Caucus Records (http://archon.lib.uh.edu/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&id=464)
Houston Area Women's Center Records http://archon.lib.uh.edu/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&id=351
Houston Area Women's Center Photographs http://archon.lib.uh.edu/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&id=349
Houston Area Women's Center Videos http://archon.lib.uh.edu/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&id=350
Scope and Contents
The collection arrived in little discernable order and the processor in consultation with the archivist has imposed an order. The collection is arranged primarily in chronological order and is divided into five series. Series two, three and four are based upon chronological and geographical divisions in Stewart's life: Pre-West Virginia University, West Virginia University, and Houston. Series One, Personal, contains information not easily assigned to the other series, and which spans most of Stewart's life. Series five, Ephemera, contains items such as tote bags, posters, newspaper clippings and plaques.
Detailed List of Contents
- Personal, 1924-2000
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains nine folders dating from 1924 to 2000, arranged chronologically. It is divided into two sub-series, Biographical Information and Photographs. The series includes a short biography, curricula vitae, photographs and information spanning most of Stewart's life. The photographs are arranged chronologically by decade. Of note is a photograph of Josephine Stewart with Texas Governor elect Ann Richards taken in 1989 and found in folder 8.
  - Biographical Information
    - 1924-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs
    - 1920s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1930s (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1940s (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1950s (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1960s (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1970s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1980s (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Pre-West Virginia University, 1940-1964
  This series contains thirty-six folders dating from the 1940s to 1964. The items concern Stewart's life prior to her employment at West Virginia University in 1964. The series is divided into four sub-series, which are arranged chronologically: Correspondence, Miscellaneous, Social Work Practice, and Booklets. The sub-series Social Work Practice contains papers relating to Stewart's work at various public and private social welfare agencies and hospitals. Notes relating to therapy sessions with particular groups comprise the majority of the material in this sub-series. The sub-series Booklets contains assorted booklets, including reports, studies, journals, and brochures about hospitals and clinics. Some of the booklets do not pertain to social work, but have been included in this sub-series because of their date. The sub-series Miscellaneous contains information about Stewart's military service, and a copy of her master's thesis.
  - Correspondence
    - 1940s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Veterans Administration, 1946, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - University of Pittsburgh, 1947, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Master's Thesis, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Social Work Practice
    - University of California, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Public Welfare Department, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Public Welfare Department, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Papers, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Psychiatric Hospital Relatives Orientation Group, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Group Counseling, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Parent's Group, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - United Community Services of Detroit, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Adolescent Girls, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Married Couples' Group, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Thursday Father's Group, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Booklets
    - A Marriage Proposal, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Program Planning, A Handbook for Social Group Workers, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Preliminary Report on an Experimental Project in Supervision in Clinical Psychology, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Techniques of Student and Staff Supervision, 1950-1953 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Shall We Have Witch Hunt?, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - American Association of Psychiatric Social Workers, Members, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Larue D. Carter Memorial Hospital, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Menninger Foundations, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Adams County Public Assistance Study, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Journal of Clinical Psychology, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Use of Group Techniques in the Family Agency, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - The Sex Offender, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Interviewing in the Social Services, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - University of Wisconsin School of Social Work (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Walnut Hills High School Directory, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Developing Discussion Leaders, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Social Group Work with the Aged, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Social Work with Groups, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Social Group Work Practice Elaborated, University of Pittsburgh, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Sing Along the Way, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
- West Virginia University, 1964-1975
  This series contains sixty-one folders dating from 1964 to 1975, and it includes materials concerning Stewart's employment at West Virginia University. This series is divided into seven sub-series: Correspondence, Administrative, Classes, Fieldwork, Academic Papers, Booklets, and Social Work Practice. All of the sub-series have been arranged chronologically, except Classes and Academic Papers. The sub-series Classes is arranged by the course number of the class rather than chronologically, which is how Stewart had this material organized. Some of the folders contain information on a particular class from different semesters, years, or institutions. This material was kept together because Stewart organized it that way; she appears to have used the same teaching materials year after year. The Academic Papers sub-series contains papers written by professors and students and is arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Correspondence
    - 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Administrative
    - West Virginia University Brochures, 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Tenure and Academic Freedom, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Track B Package, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Practice Committee, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Training Meeting I, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Affirmative Action, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Letterhead, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Classes
    - Social Work 61, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Social Work 210-220, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Social Work 280, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Social Work 298, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Social Work 301, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Social Work 302, 303, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Social Work 304, 1946-1959 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Social Work 305, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Social Work 305, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Social Work 305, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Social Work 305 Papers, 1965-1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Social Work 312, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Social Work 317, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Social Work 322, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Social Work 340, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Social Work 341, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Social Work 351, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Social Work 360, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Social Work 388, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Social Work 421, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Social Work 441, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Social Work 451, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Social Work 480, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous Classes, 1964, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - West Virginia Department of Welfare Classes, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - West Virginia Department of Welfare Classes, January-August 1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - West Virginia Department of Welfare Classes, September-December 1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - West Virginia Department of Welfare Classes, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - West Virginia Department of Welfare Classes, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fieldwork
    - Group Work, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Group Work, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Field Instruction Manual, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Academic Papers
    - A - E, 1965-1972 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - F - H, 1965-1960 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - I - L, 1965-1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - M - P, 1966-1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Q - R, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - S, 1966-1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - T, 1964-1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - U - Z, 1965-1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Book Review, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Lecture, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Booklets
    - Messiah, His Redemptive Career, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Report of Division of Social Work West Virginia University, Part 1, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - The Social Worker and West Virginia's Economic Dilemma, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Survey Report on Mental Health, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Accreditation Review, Volume I, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Accreditation Review Volume II, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Community Survey, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Social Work Practice
    - Social Security Act Information, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1964-1970 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Social Work, 1964-1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Portsmouth Workshop, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - West Virginia Welfare Conferences, 1965-1972 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Pennsylvania Association on Probation, Parole and Correction Conference, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Veteran's Administration Social Workers, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Symposium on Rural Social Work, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Houston
  This series contains 149 folders dating from 1975 to 1990, and it concerns Stewart's time in Houston. The series is divided into nine sub-series, which are arranged chronologically: National Association of Social Workers; National Association of Social Workers, Chapters; Council on Social Work Education; Women's Movement; United States Commission on Civil Rights; Social Work Practice; Gay/Lesbian Issues; Booklets; and Miscellaneous/Personal. The National Association of Social Workers (NASW) is an organization with which Stewart was heavily involved in the 1980s. Although some of the NASW material dates from before Stewart moved to Houston, it has been placed in this series in order to keep it with other NASW items. The same applies to the Council on Social Work Education (CSWE). At times, NASW and CSWE mailed out envelopes of information; the dates of material in each envelope varied and often included some things with dates up to one year old. The majority of these materials were still in their original envelopes from NASW and CSWE when Stewart's papers entered the archives. Despite the variety of dates, the material from each envelope has been kept together as originally compiled and sent. The date on each folder refers to the postmarked date on the envelope. Most of these mailings concern gay/lesbian issues. Other sub-series contain material on the women's movement, in which Stewart was involved, as well as items concerning social work practice.
  - National Association of Social Workers (NASW)
    - Statement of Reference, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Study Projects, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Pamphlets, 1968-1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - West Virginia Chapter, Spring Meeting, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Mailings, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Insurance, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Sixth NASW Professional Symposium, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Mailings, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Mailings, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Travis Peterson Paper, February 1982 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - National Task Force on Lesbian and Gay Issues, Meeting Minutes, May 1982 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Mailings, May 1982 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Fourth National Lesbian/Gay Health Conference, June 1982 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Mailings, August 1982 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Mailings, October 1982 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Gay/Lesbian Resource Manual, Part 1, October 1982 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Gay/Lesbian Resource Manual, Part 2, October 1982 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Mailings, November 1982 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Mailings, December 1982 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Washington Rally, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting, Part 1, January 1983 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Annual Meeting, Part 2, January 1983 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Mailings, February 1983 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Mailings, April 1983 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Mailings, May 1983 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Mailings, June 1983 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Mailings, July 1983 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Mailings, August 1983 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Mailings, September 1983 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - National Office, October 1983 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Mailings, October 1983 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Mailings, November 1983 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Professional Symposium, November 1983 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Directory, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Resource Manual, Part 1, Rough Draft, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Resource Manual, Part 2, Rough Draft, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Resource Manual, Part 1, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Resource Manual, Part 2, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Mailings, January 1984 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Mailings, January 1984 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Mailings, February 1984 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Mailings, March 1984 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Mailings, April 1984 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Mailings, July 1984 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Mailings, August 1984 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Mailings, October 1984 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Mailings, December 1984 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Services Packet, One, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Services Packet, Two, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Mailings, January 1985 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Mailings, February 1985 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Mailings, March 1985 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - National Office, March 1985 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Mailings, April 1985 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Women's Issues Conference, May 1985 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Women's Issues Conference, May 1986 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - National Association of Social Workers (NASW), Chapters
    - Texas Chapter - Mailings, November 1981 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Texas Chapter - Mailings, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Texas Chapter - Sixth Annual Conference, October 1982 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Texas Chapter - Mailings, 1983-1985 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Texas Chapter - Mailings, September 1988 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Texas Chapter - Mailings, October 1988 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Texas Chapter - Mailings, September-December 1989 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Texas Chapter - Mailings, October 1989 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Texas Chapter - Mailings, November 1989 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Texas Chapter - Mailings, December 1989 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Texas Chapter - Political Action for Candidate Election, 1989-1990 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Texas Chapter - Mailings, January 1990 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Texas Chapter - Directory, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Maine Chapter - Mailings, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Illinois Chapter - Mailings, 1984-1985 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Council on Social Work Education
    - Group Work Records, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Source Book of Readings on Teaching Social Work, Part 1, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Source Book of Readings on Teaching Social Work, Part 2, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Mailings, 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Mailings, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Mailings, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Mailings, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Mailings, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Mailings, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Mailings, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Mailings, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Mailings, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Mailings, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Mailings, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Mailings, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Mailings, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Mailings, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Mailings, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Mailings, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Women's Movement
    - NOW National Conference, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Young Women's Christian Association Bylaws, 1975-1979 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Battered Women Pamphlets/Newsletters, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Feminist Movement, Miscellaneous, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Houston Area Women's Center Bylaws, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Battered Women Information, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Houston Town Meeting, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - National Coalition Against Domestic Violence, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Women in Action, Women's Information and Referral Exchange Service (WIRES), 1978 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Danish Clinic Study, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Houston Area Women's Center Board of Directors, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Houston Area Women's Center Financial Information, 1979-1980 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Houston Area Women's Center Miscellaneous, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Women in Management, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - NOW National Issues Conference, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Bibliography - Woman Abuse, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Discrimination Against Women, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - United States Commission on Civil Rights
    - Packet, January 1978 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Papers A - B, January 1978 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Papers C - L, January 1978 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Papers, M - R, January 1978 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Papers, S - Z, January 1978 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Resumes, January 1978 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Social Work Practice
    - Youth Development Center, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlets, 1972 - 1990 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Newsletters, 1974-1980 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Legislation, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Texas Hospital Association, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - University of Houston, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Medicare Information, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Alcoholism Information, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Gerontology Information, 1982-1983 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Association for Women in Social Work, 1984-1985 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Clinical Social Work Journal, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Menninger Clinic Seventh Annual Conference, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous AIDS Information, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Mental Illness, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Social Workers Making a Political Difference, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Texas Society for Clinical Social Work, Directory, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - University of Houston Futures Conference, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Articles, 1977-1990 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Human Serve Fund, undated (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous Social Work, undated (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Gay/Lesbian Issues
    - Third National Lesbian and Gay Health Conference, 1980-1982 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Second Annual West Coast Women's Music and Cultural Festival, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous Gay/Lesbian Information, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Booklets
    - The Giving Tree, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Sylvia Plath, Crossing the Water, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Getting Clear, Body Work for Women, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Working with People Called Patients, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Current Concepts in Rehabilitative Medicine, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - A Goddess in My Shoes, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous/Personal
    - Correspondence, 1975-1989 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Address Book, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Retirement, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Ephemera
  This series is dated 1979 to 1990, although it contains a number of items which cannot be dated. It is divided into five sub-series, which are arranged chronologically: Conference Items, Newspapers, Plaques, Miscellaneous, and Posters. This series contains items such as tote bags, a bumper sticker, newspaper clippings, and plaques. The posters have been placed in an oversized folder, labeled as box 22.
  - Conference Items
    - NASW Insurance Trust notepad holder, 1987 (Box 20, Item 1)
    - Social Work '88: Choices and Challenges tote bag, 1988 (Box 20, Item 2)